# SINDHU NARAYANASWAMY

sxn180011@utdallas.edu | (469) 931-9218 | 800 W Renner Rd, Richardson, TX 75080 | linkedin.com/in/Sindhu-Narayanaswamy

### **SUMMARY**

Software engineer with experience in developing real-time embedded software on ARM processors; Implemented Feedback Control Systems and Sensor Fusion Algorithms in C, C++, Python and MATLAB, Experience in Hardware – Software Integration; Optimized Deep Learning Models; Knowledge of Functional Safety Standards and Controls Software Tools.

### PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

## Embedded Software Engineer Intern, Bosch, Ann Arbor, MI

May 2019 - Aug 2019

- Developed body control software in Embedded C to realize automatic headlights and wiper control; Simulated the state flow diagram and control system using model-based tool ASCET to ensure algorithm robustness.
- Integrated AUTOSAR architecture and configured Basic Software for Infineon Aurix-TC277 and improved development velocity by optimizing AUTOSAR workflow. Also programmed API to facilitate HW SW interaction.
- Integrated and Tested ECU software using ISOLAR-EVE (virtual ECU) tool leveraging the AUTOSAR standard, thus enhancing software quality at an early point in the development process.

#### Software Engineer, Bosch, Bangalore, India

Sep 2016 - Jul 2018

- Developed Diagnostic Software for parameter monitoring from Application SW, and Basic SW (CAN, DCOM). Automated unit testing and component testing for C code using CANTATA++. Achieved 10% improvement in SW quality. Used Vector tools (CANalyzer) to conduct release testing in HIL environment.
- Created State estimation (Kalman Filter), sensor fusion algorithms and control (state) flow for Electronic Stability Controller functionalities based on customer requirements, while ensuring compliance to ISO 26262 standards.
- Developed AUTOSAR embedded software for Electronic Stability Program ECU following V-model of ASPICE, from requirement analysis using Doors to unit test, validation and verification for high priority projects such as Ford V36x Transit, Ford F150, P552 to achieve ASPICE compliance.

# Software Engineer Intern, Indian Space Research Organization, Bangalore, India

Jan 2016 - Apr 2016

- Designed a system-level Simulink model for 16-Point FFT to validate proposed DSP architecture. Verified 4096 Point FFT algorithm accuracy using MATLAB code, Programmed Radix-2<sup>2</sup> SDF(DSP) algorithm in VHDL and targeted into Xilinx Virtex-4 FPGA, which optimized HW utilization to 81% on FPGA, and improved OFDM system performance.
- Tested this DSP model on OFDM modulator/demodulator with real-time inputs, obtained a precision error of 0.2%.
  Implemented this architecture on OFDMA based WiMAX communication modules and improved their efficiency by utilizing an FPGA based FFT program.

### Embedded Systems Intern, Technophilia Systems, Mumbai, India

Jul 2014 – Aug 2014

• Developed a real-time embedded software for a vehicle tracking system with GPS, accelerometer and GSM modules on ARM processor to improve accuracy of vehicle location by using sensor fusion algorithms.

# Embedded Software Programmer, Tenet Technetronics, Bangalore, India

May 2014 - Jun 2014

• Developed a low-cost automated obstacle avoidance system based on C using Atmega328 microcontroller to prevent crashes of remote-control toy cars using ultrasonic sensor.

# **EDUCATION**

Master of Science – Electrical EngineeringGPA: 3.79May 2020University of Texas at Dallas, Richardson, TXGPA: 3.80May 2016Bachelor of Engineering – Electrical and ElectronicsGPA: 3.80May 2016Visvesvaraya Technological University, KA, India

#### **OTHER PROJECTS**

# Adaptive Cruise Control (ACC) and Lane Centering for robot vehicle

Jan 2020 - Present

• Developed Lateral and Longitudinal control of robot vehicle in C with PID controller and Ultrasonic Sensor on ATmega328 microcontroller. Calibrated the sensor and designed Kalman filter to determine the best State Estimation.

## Self-Supervised Deep Learning-Based Speech Enhancement

Oct 2019 - Dec 2019

- Trained Convolutional Neural Network model using MATLAB and Python for Speech enhancement in environments with machinery & babble noise without any clean speech (Self-supervised model).
- Optimized to improve Output SNR by 37.5% and reduced software latency to 56.4 micro-seconds.

# Speaker Identification on Fearless Steps: Apollo 11 NASA Corpus

Nov 2019 - Dec 2019

- Developed a speaker recognition model based on traditional Gaussian Mixture Model and Deep Learning Model using Kaldi tool (C++, python and shell scripting) to identify speakers, and increased Top-5 Accuracy by 10%.
- Implemented pre-trained i-vector and x-vector model for each speaker using NASA Apollo 11 Corpus Dataset.

# Pedestrian recognition using Deep Learning

Feb 2019 - Mar 2019

 Developed (Faster R-CNN) Deep-Learning based model using Keras framework for pedestrian recognition which was pre-trained on Nvidia GPU with KITTI vision Benchmark dataset to improve the software latency and accuracy.

### **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

**Programming/Engineering tools**: Embedded C, Misra C, C++, Python, Matlab, Simulink, Multisim, LabView, Android Studio, ETAS ASCET, ETAS ISOLAR-AB, Vector DaVinci, CANoe, CANalyzer, ETAS LABCAR **Sensors:** Ultrasonic, IR, Camera, IMU, wheel speed sensor, steering angle sensor, RADAR

Hardware: Arduino, Raspberry Pi, FPGA, MSP430, Arm Cortex-M4, Atmel 8051, ETAS LABCAR (HIL testing)